<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech on Junk Drawer</title>
    <link>https://johncraven.github.io/categories/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tech on Junk Drawer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.7</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 23:18:02 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://johncraven.github.io/categories/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Todo Update: First Steps in AJAX world</title>
      <link>https://johncraven.github.io/posts/todo-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 23:18:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johncraven.github.io/posts/todo-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Continuing &lt;a href=&#34;https://johncraven.github.io/posts/todo-2/&#34;&gt;this todo project&lt;/a&gt;, I thought it would be a good time to dip into a little JS. So far the site was built entirely with Django server rendered templates. To get started with some progressive enhancements I picked out a few changes I could make on the frontend with JS without needing to update the Django views or create API endpoints yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-product&#34;&gt;Final product&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a gif after the changes. You&amp;rsquo;ll notice that delete buttons now open a modal in a few cases. What might be trickier to see in the gif is that deleting items from a list now happens without a full page refresh.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Todo Update: Field properties, Comments and Styling</title>
      <link>https://johncraven.github.io/posts/todo-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 13:02:50 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johncraven.github.io/posts/todo-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with extending the &lt;a href=&#34;https://johncraven.github.io/posts/todo-1/&#34;&gt;toy Django app&lt;/a&gt; I was working on. I wanted to focus on getting more backend experience with Django while also getting more understanding for web dev basics for HTML/CSS/JS, so I restricted myself to Django and vanilla CSS/JS for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;current-state&#34;&gt;Current state&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://johncraven.github.io/posts/todo-2/site-example.gif#center&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-features&#34;&gt;New features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added some basic CSS container and form styling with a little neubrutalism inspiration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added more properties on the default todo items; due dates, descriptions, priority&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The list view on the homepage includes the description and flags for overdue and high priority items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The detail page now has a basic comment section, making use of the &lt;code&gt;django.contrib.humanize&lt;/code&gt; package to format dates into relevant strings like &amp;ldquo;now&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;an hour ago&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And of course, additions to the test suite for new functionality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;process&#34;&gt;Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time around I am trying to take a more project-oriented approach to learning, and integrating more LLM tools into my workflow. Since I&amp;rsquo;m doing this to learn on my own I&amp;rsquo;m leaning more on the side of using the llm tools to guide me rather than edit code directly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple Todo Site</title>
      <link>https://johncraven.github.io/posts/todo-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 19:53:37 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johncraven.github.io/posts/todo-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been working in an IT management role for a few years now, primarily focused on data engineering and integrations with analytical instrumentation. Unfortunately, I rarely get the chance to develop hands-on coding skills at work, so I thought it would be fun to take up some side projects and tinker around. To get started I made a simple to-do website with Django. The site is basic CRUD functionality just to help jog my memory on how everything fits together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux Update 🐧</title>
      <link>https://johncraven.github.io/posts/linux-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 18:29:40 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johncraven.github.io/posts/linux-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been tinkering around with Linux Mint at home for a few weeks now and decided to write a quick update on how it has been going so far. I decided to update my home computer to dual boot into Linux Mint and Win11 after getting annoyed with the Microsoft pushing onedrive and the m365 accounts on bootup. I did still keep the windows partition active as a fallback, particularly for software compatiblity if I don&amp;rsquo;t want to fuss with wine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
